Furth, Josef Herbert; Papers ger036
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Typescripts and published versions of essays, speeches and position papers, 1932-1981; 5; 181 folders
  - "Capitalism: Achievements and Shortcomings". Speech text, King-Smith Studio, 1945 March 7 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 23)
  - "Race Relations and Retail Trade in Chester County, Pennsylvania", 1945 November 12; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 24)
  - "Industrial Consolidations in Austria", ca. 1947; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 25)
  - "Competition and Cooperation in the World Economy". Speech text, Howard University, 1947 March 29 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 26)
  - "Currency Conversion and Repressed Inflation", ca. November 1949; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 27)
  - "Repressed Inflation and Currency Reform in Western Europe", 1949 November 22; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 28)
    Published version in Portuguese as "Inflação Reprimida e Reforma Monetária na Alemanha Ocidental", Revista Brasileira de Economia, IV, No. 1 (March 1950), 59-79.
  - "International Economic Problems of Western Germany". Speech text, Richmond Export-Import Club, 1949 December 14 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous texts, 1950 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 30)
  - "The Case Against Discrimination", ca. 1950; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 31)
  - "The Future of the Dollar Gap", ca. 1950; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 32)
  - "Partial Disequilibrium and Monetary Policy", ca. 1950; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 33)
  - "Financial Stability and Economic Progress", 1950 January 11; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 34)
  - "A Ação dos Bancos Centrais e o Equilíbrio Econômico", Portuguese translation of "Central Bank Policies and Economic Equilibrium" published in Revista Brasileira de Economia, IV, No. 4 (December 1950), 43-70, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 35)
  - "Germany's Problems in Postwar Europe". Speech text, American Institute of Banking, Richmond, 1950 March 28 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 36)
  - "Effects of Abolition of Exchange and Quantitative Trade Restrictions", 1950 May 22; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 37)
  - "Central Banking and the Problems of Our Time". Draft of speech for Gov. Matt Szymczak, 1950 August 3 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 38)
  - "Monetary Policy and the International Economy". Draft of speech for Gov. Matt Szymczak, 1950 October 20 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 39)
  - "Notes on the Philosophical Basis of Monetary Policy". Draft of speech for Gov. Matt Szymczak, 1950 November 1 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 40)
  - "The sterling problem and the principle of non-discrimination", ca. 1951; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 41)
  - "Our Fight Against Inflation", 1951 March 5; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 42)
  - "Domestic Finance and International Balance in Germany", 1951 March 20; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous texts, 1952 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 44)
  - "Monetary Policy and Economic Equilibrium in Central Europe", 1952 March; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 45)
  - "Monetary Aspects of International Economic Policy". Speech text, Industrial College of the Armed Forces, 1952 March 25 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 46)
  - "US Monetary Policy, 1951-52". Panel discussion, IMF, 1952 April 17 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 47)
  - "Comments on Some Problems of Currency Convertibility". Speech text, American Economic Association, Chicago, 1952 December 26-1952 December 29 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 48)
  - "In Western Europe". Published version in The Conference Board Business Record, X, No. 1 (January 1953), 19-21, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 49)
  - "Problems of Sterling Convertibility". Speech text, Brookings Institution, 1953 January 29 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 50)
  - "Problems of Currency Convertibility". Seminar, Johns Hopkins University, 1953 April 15 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 51)
  - "Problems of US Trade With Europe". Speech text, Minneapolis Economic Club, 1953 April 30 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 52)
  - "Dollar Area and Sterling Area -- A Case Study in Applied Theory of International Finance". Speech text, Federal Reserve Bank, Minneapolis, 1953 May 2 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 53)
  - "A Stock-taking of Bretton Woods Objectives -- Discussion". Published version in American Economic Review (May 1953), 96-98, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 54)
  - "Yesterday is not Tomorrow -- Effects of a U.S. Recession on the World Economy", 1953 October 16; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous texts, 1954 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 56)
  - "Problems of Convertibility". Speech text, Univ. of Chicago, 1954 March 18 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 57)
  - "Notes on Some Problems of Convertibility", 1954 July 15; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 58)
  - "Comments on Mr. Mendershausen's Paper on Convertibility and Economic Nationalism", 1954 September 8; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 59)
  - "The 'Balance-Sheet' Approach to Monetary Problems", 1954 September 22; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 60)
  - "Income Effect of Foreign Trade". Speech text, Georgetown Univ, 1954 December 9 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 61)
  - Miscellaneous texts, 1955 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 62)
  - "Monetary Policy and the Perils of Prosperity", ca. 1955; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 63)
  - "Financial Policy", 1955 May 31; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 64)
  - "Cooperative Banking in the United States", 1955 July 7; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 65)
  - "Commercial Banking in the United States", 1955 August; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 66)
    Published version in German as "Die Kommerzbanken in den Vereinigten Staaten", Wirtschaftsberichte, VIII, No. 26 (June 1956), 5-14.
  - "One Year of Inflation: The U.K. Balance of Payments in 1954-55". Speech text, Graduate School of Public Administration, Harvard University, 1955 November 25 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 67)
  - Miscellaneous texts, 1966 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 68)
  - "Comments on State Department Draft on Foreign Reporting, Subchapter 230, Economic Development of Underdeveloped Areas", 1956 March 26; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 69)
  - "Financial Stability in Western Europe". Speech text, School of Advanced International Studies, Conference for Corporation Executives, 1956 April 3 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 70)
  - "Notes sur quelques problèmes du développement économique". Published in Cahiers Série F 3 (June 10, 1956), 1-16, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 71)
  - "Indicators of Inflation in Western Europe 1952-1955". Published version in The Review of Economics and Statistics, No. 3 August 1956), 335-338, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 72)
  - Miscellaneous texts, 1957 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 73)
  - Miscellaneous texts, 1958 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 74)
  - "Chapter XIII: International Relations and the Federal Reserve System", 1958 June (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 75)
    Typescript of chapter for Prochnow book.
  - "Federal Reserve and NAC", 1958 September 18; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 76)
  - "Draft Remarks for Governor Shepardson", 1958 October; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 77)
  - "The United States Balance of Payments in the Recession". Speech text, Harvard Univ, 1958 November (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 78)
  - Miscellaneous texts, 1959 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 79)
  - "International Transactions", 1959 January 20; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 80)
  - "The Role of Gold in the United States Monetary System", 1959 February 16; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 81)
  - "Changes in Gold Reserves", 1959 March 2; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 82)
  - "International Economic Policies of NATO Members. Speech text, Atlantic Congress of Committee for Economic Development, London, 1959 April 14 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 83)
  - Miscellaneous texts, 1960 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 84)
  - "The United States as a World Investor". Speech text, National Industrial Conference Board, New York, 1960 May 19 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 85)
  - "Unbalanced International Accounts: Diagnosis and Therapy", 1960 July 19; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 86)
    Published version The American Economic Review, LI, No. 2 (May 1961), 430-438.
  - "Comments on 'The Loan Policy of the Export-Import Bank'". Speech text, Southern Economic Association, 1960 November 19 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 87)
  - "Measurement of U.S. Balance-of-Payments Deficit", 1960 November 14; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 88)
  - Miscellaneous texts, 1961 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 89)
  - "Capital movements, balance of payments, gold transfers, and interest-rate differences", 1961 March 3; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 90)
  - "Theory and Policy of Foreign Economic Aid", 1961 April 4; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 91)
  - "The International Position of the U.S. Dollar". Published in Current Problems of International Monetary Problems, 1961 September 18-1961 September 21 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 92)
  - "Das Federal-Reserve-System und sein Gebäude in Washington". Published in Die Bundesbank. Zeitschrift für die Bediensteten der Deutschen Bundesbank, No. 8 (November 1961), 8-14, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 93)
  - "Problems of U.S. Balance of Payments", 1962 January 2; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 94)
  - "Federal Reserve Operations in Foreign Exchange", 1962 April 27; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 95)
  - "Problems of International Liquidity", 1962 November 5; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 96)
  - "International Finance and Federal Reserve", 1962 December 6; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 97)
  - "AEA Discussion Paper". Speech text, Pittsburgh, 1962 December 29 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 98)
  - "Theorie und Politik der wirtschaftlichen Auslandshilfe". Published version in Handbuch der Finanzwissenschaft (Tübingen: J.C.B. Mohr, 1963), 156-183, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 99)
  - "International Functions of the Federal Reserve". Speech text, Brookings Fellows, 1963 February 14 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 100)
  - "Additional comments on tax measures to reduce the U.S. payments deficit", 1963 March 18; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 101)
  - "International Monetary Equilibrium -- Discussion". Published version in American Economic Review (May 1963), 144-146, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 102)
  - "Role of Gold in International Reserves", 1963 May 15; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 103)
  - "Reserve Currencies as International Reserve Assets", 1963 May 17; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 104)
  - "Remarks of Chairman William McC. Martin Before Georgetown University Bankers' Forum". Speech text, 1963 October 5 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 105)
  - "International Liquidity -- Problems and Solutions". Published version of speech, Economics Seminar, Pennsylvania State University, 1963 November 5 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 106)
  - "The 'New Mix' and the Adjustment Process", 1964 January 6; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 107)
  - "Improvement of Reserve Currency Program", 1964 January 11; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 108)
  - "The Role of a stable Dollar in Expanding World Markets". Draft of speech for Gov. Mitchell, 1964 February 6 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 109)
  - "Areas of Agreement among the 'Ten'", 1964 April 22; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 110)
  - "The U.S. Balance of International Payments". Speech text, Investment Bankers Association, 1964 April 27 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 111)
  - "Problems of International Liquidity", 1964 June 24; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 112)
  - "The U.S. Balance of Payments and International Capital Flows". Speech text for Gov. Robertson, 1964 June 30 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 113)
  - "Research Functions of International Finance Division", 1964 July 2; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 114)
  - "Relations Between Federal Reserve and Treasury". Speech text, IMF trainees, 1964 July 31 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 115)
  - "International Developments and monetary policy". Published version in Business Conditions (October 1964), 5-12, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 116)
  - "Capital Flows and Balance-of-Payments Policy". Speech draft for Gov. Mitchell, 1964 December 23 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 117)
  - "Professor James on the Theory of Monetary Policy". Published version in Zeitschrift für Nationalökonomie, XXV, No. 1 / 2, 199-203, 1965 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 118)
  - "Monetary Policy and Balance of Payments". Speech text, Foreign Students Council, 1965 January 27 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 119)
  - "The 'asymmetry' of the reserve-currency system", 1965 April 13; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 120)
  - "General Agreement on Balance-of-Payment Adjustments", 1965 April 16; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 121)
  - "New Challenges for Monetary Policy", 1965 July 2; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 122)
  - "Evaluation of reserve currency system", 1965 July 23; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 123)
  - "Question 3: Why do capital movements among industrial countries sometimes give rise to a transfer problem?", 1965 September 1; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 124)
  - "Comments on draft papers on monetary reform for submission to the Deputies of the Group of Ten", 1966 January 19; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 125)
  - "Problems of International Liquidity". Speech text, IMF Special Trainee Seminar, 1966 January 20 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 126)
  - "Monetary Policy and International Economic Relations". Speech text, Foreign Students Council, 1966 January 26 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 127)
  - "Das Bundes-Reserve-System in der Internationalen Finanzpolitik", 1966 May 12; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 128)
  - "Limits of Monetary Policy", 1966 August 24; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 129)
  - "Should the U.S. Treasury Lower its Buying Price for Gold?", 1966 September 30; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 130)
  - "Domestic and international goals of monetary policy", 1966 December 23; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 131)
  - "International Responsibilities of the Federal Reserve", 1967 January 3; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 132)
  - "Once more: Rueff on gold", 1967 January 12; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 133)
  - "US payments deficit for 1966", 1967 January 24; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 134)
  - "On Taxing the Aged", 1967 August 7; typescript, clippings (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 135)
  - "Theory of Capital and Investment". Speech text, Economic Review, 1967 August 24 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 136)
  - "Papers on Federal Reserve", 1968 January 23-1968 January 29; typescripts (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 137)
  - "Problems of U.S. Investment in European Industrial Enterprises", 1968 August; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 138)
  - "Barriers to Investment Abroad as Tools of Payment Policy". Speech text, Georgetown University, 1968 September 26 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 139)
    Published version in Law and Contemporary Problems (Winter 1969), 64-83.
  - "Some preliminary comments on the problem of 'shell' branches of US banks in the Bahamas", 1968 October 17; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 140)
  - "Short-term Capital Movements and US Payments Balance". Speech text, Harvard University, 1968 October 21 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 141)
  - "'Shell' Branches and Subsidiaries of U.S. Banks in the Bahamas", 1968 October 24; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 142)
  - "Pros and Cons of the Crawling Peg", 1969; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 143)
  - "Barriers to Investment Abroad as Tools of Payment Policy", 1969 February; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 144)
  - "Outlook for the US Balance of Payments". Speech text, Industrial College, 1969 February 7 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 145)
  - "Introduction to International Economics -- Outline", 1969 April 15; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 1)
  - "Comments on Proposal for a Central American Stabilization Fund by R. Triffin and R. N. Cooper (Yale University, 1968)", 1969 June 13; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 2)
  - "International Economic Problems of Less Developed Countries", 1970 January 9; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 3)
  - "Comments on the Administration's Economic Program", 1971 August 16; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 4)
  - "International Dollar Liquidity and the Eurodollar Market", 1973 February 26; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 5)
  - "Problems of International Financial Policy". Speech text, Industrial War College, 1981 May 14 (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 6)
  - Reviews by Furth of works by others, 5.152
    - Brown, W.A., Jr.The International Gold Standard Reinterpreted, 1940; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 7)
    - van der Valk, H.M.H.A.Egalisatiefondsen en Monetaire Pollitiek in England en Nederland, 1947 September (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 8)
    - Harmssen, G.W.Reparationen, Sozialprodukt, Lebensstandard: Versuch einer Wirtsschaftsbilanz, 1948 December (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 9)
    - Kerschagel, Richard.Handelspolitik. Das Geld von heute. Abriss der Finanzwissenschaft, 1950 September (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 10)
    - Economic Commission for Europe.Economic Survey of Europe in 1949, 1950 December (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 11)
    - Ellis, Howard S.The Economics of Freedom, 1951; proofs (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 12)
    - Kindleberger, Charles P.The Dollar Shortage, 1951; proofs (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 13)
    - Balough, T.Germany: An Experiment in "Planning" by the "Free" Price Mechanism; Roepke, Wilhelm. Ist die Deutsche Wirtschaftspolitik richtig?, 1952 February (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 14)
    - Graf, Willi.Der Aussenhandel zwischen marktwirtschaftlich organisierten und zentralgeleiteten Volkswirtschaften, 1952 February (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 15)